欢迎短暂休息后再次回来
So welcome back again after a short break
呃，我们到了，让我介绍一下我们的下一位演讲者
Uh , we are here and let me introduce our next speaker
一
Um
我个人很荣幸地说，CD 项目的首席电影程序员
i'm personally honored to say that lead cinematic programmer from cd project
菲利普·皮埃尔·钦斯基的红色是我们今天的客人
Red at philip pierre chinski is our guest today
呃，欢迎睡觉
Uh , welcome sleep
嘿，你好
Hey , hello
呃，你怎么样
Uh , how are you
你今天过得怎么样
How is this your day today
那很好
That's quite fine
呃，我正在大声地准备这个演讲
Uh , i was preparing for this presentation quite loud
所以我希望
So i hope that
呃，你会喜欢的
Uh , you will like it
是的
Yeah
那么让我，呃，开始你的演讲
So let me , uh , start your presentation
我喜欢这种黄色的赛博朋克颜色
I like this yellow cyberpunk color
哇，太棒了
Wow , amazing
所以
So
呃，话不多说，上演你的
Uh , without further ado , stages yours
谢谢
Thank you
嗯，你好
Um , hello
欢迎来到我的演讲
Welcome to my presentation
嗯，我要谈谈我们的方法，呃
Um , i'm going to talk about our approach to , uh
我们相关游戏中的工具、管道和实现
Tools , pipelines and implementations in our rellatest game
本次演讲中介绍的技术和工具在部门程序游戏中意义深远
Technology and tools presented in this talk was profound within sectoral program gaming
国家研究开发中心提供
Provided by national center for research and development
项目名称：电影领域
The name of the project is cinematic field
综合技术使品质迈上新台阶
Comprehensive technology enable a new level of quality
提供独特的电影体验
in delivering unique cinematic experience
在高端开放病房猿游戏中
In high end open ward apee games
包括创新的管道解决方案和定制工具包
Including innovative pipeline solutions and custom toolkit
介绍一下我自己正在从事的常用项目
Bit about myself useveral project that i was working on
嗯，从现实泵走向两个
Um , towards two from the reality pump
呃，这是有两个扩展的狂猎
Uh , which are wild hunt with two expansions
石心、血和w
Hearts of stone and blood and w
最后是赛博朋克277
And finally cyber punk two thousand and seventy seven
这支股票的重点是什么
Which is the focus of this stock
网络PK互动场景话题
Topic of interactive scenes in a cyber pk
两千七十七真是浩瀚
Two thousand and seventy seven is really vast
很多人参与了设计的制定
And a lot of people were involved in shaping up the design
然后再交出场景
And later on delivering the scenes
我要感谢该项目的所有人
I would like to thank all to the project
参与该过程的开发人员
That the developers who participate in the process
电影设计师、商店编剧
Cinematic designers , store writers
任务设计师、程序员、游戏玩法设计师
Quest designers , programmers , gameplay designers
问a，所有的艺术家，制作人和其他人都相信我真的很难说出名字
q a , all the artist , producers and others is believed me really hard to name
每个人
Everyone
谢谢
Thank you
关于该项目 um 网络银行是开放行动
About the project um cyber bank is open word action
以夜之城为背景的冒险故事
Adventure story set in night city
夜之城是一个痴迷于权力、魅力、身体改造的巨型警察
Night city is a mega police obsessed with power , glamour , body modification
夜晚的城市生活很艰难
In night city life is hard
并且没有什么好的选择
And there is no good choices
每个决定都会产生后果，为了生存，你需要非常努力
Every decision has consequence and to survive you need to be really hard
真强
Really strong
所有那些极端的情绪
All those extreme emotions
危险的关系和曲折都在电影中得到体现
Dangerous , dangerous relationships and twists are reflected in the cinematics
而在故事里
And in the story
让我们看看包含很多内容的预告片
So let's see the trailer that contains many things
一
Um
比文字更能捕捉到电影领域的精髓
And captured the essence of the cinematic field better than than words
考验一个人的真实价值
Test of a person's true value
死亡
Death
面向
Facing
低头凝视它
Staring it down
约翰尼，我找到你了
johnny i got you
珍贵的是它的神经源性休克
Precious taking it's neurogenic shock
他快死了
he's dying
你在那里
V e you in there
啊我的头
ah my head
那现在怎么办
So what now
现在
now
你会发现做一件美丽的事情需要什么
You find out what it is you need to do a thing of beauty
我知道你一生中从未对任何事情退缩过
I know you've never backed down from anything in your life
即使你可能应该让你穿过夜晚的城市
Even when you may be should have you go through night city
驾驶出租车时知道一颗流弹可能会杀死你
Knowing a stray bullet could end you while ailing a cab
但这从来没有阻止你采取行动
But that's never stopped you from taking action
你相信你欺骗了死亡
You believe you cheated death
是死亡欺骗了你
It is death that has cheated you
如果你要杀，那就杀吧
If you gotta kill , kill
如果你要把它全部烧毁
If you gotta burn it all to the ground
然后让它燃烧
Then let it burn
告诉我地面上是搬不出我家的
Tell me on the ground is of no move out of my house
不，你永远不会消失
No you'll never fade away
你对我做了什么
What you did to me
我知道
I know
所以我如何找到一种方法，但我想到了美
so how i find a way but i think of beauty
无人先生，你宁愿生活成碎片吗
Would you rather live in pieces mr nobody
或者一直下去
Or go down for all times
在荣耀的火焰中
In a blaze of glory
并且永远不会消失
and will never fade away
我们永远不会消失
we'll never fade away
喝我的话我想指导你
Drink my talk i would like to guide you
通过交互式电影的关键方面
Through the interactive cinematics key aspects
接下来我将向您展示我们的场景工具集
Next i will show you our toolset for the scenes
它的外观、工作原理以及我将使用它
How it looks , how it works and i will use it
最后，嗯
And at the end , um
我的谈话，呃
Of my talk , uh
我将展示我们在网络银行这样的大型游戏中的演出方法
I will show our approach to the staging in such big game as cyber bank
two thousand and seventy seven
网络银行与冬季免费有很大不同
Cyber bank is very different from the winter free
也就是说，我们必须采取新的方法
And that's , we had to come with new approaches
那件事，呃，当然也不例外
That things , uh , of course was not the exception
让我们来看看这些关键方面
So let's go through those key aspects
这也说明了这两款游戏之间的差异
Which illustrates also the differences between those two games
第一个方面，我们也很有发言权
The first aspect , it was us also very vocal
这是视角
It's perspective
第一人称视角是沉浸式故事的自然选择
First person perspective view is natural choice for immersive story
展现沉浸式商店
To showing immersive store
然而，这会导致某些复杂性
However , it leads to certain complexities
fpp 中的相机很难制作动画
The camera in fpp is difficult to animate
以及动画数据中的任何错误
And any error in animation data
稍后对那些动画数据进行计算
Later on calculation on those animation data data
之后动画图状态的变化对于玩家来说是非常明显的
And later on animation graph state changes are very visible to the player
我想给你看一个例子
I want to show you one example
嗯，首先打破 fpp 视图的沉浸感有多容易
Um , how easy to break the immersion in fpp view first
嗯，请关注左侧动画
Um please focus on the left hand side animation
观察几秒钟
Watch it for a few seconds
慢慢来
Take your time
可能注意到现在将注意力集中在右手动画上几秒钟
probably notice that now focus on the right hand animation for a few seconds
非常光滑
It's very smooth
你有没有注意到这个突然的动作有多么令人恼火
Have you noticed how irritating was this sudden movement on
在左侧动画的相机上
On the camera on the left animation
所以你可以理解那些相机后背有多痛苦
So you can understand how painful those camera backs are
他们如何给我们带来问题
How they was problematic for us
这就是问题所在
And here what was the problem
被指控的错误，因为动画没有按时加载
The error accused , because the animation didn't load on time
第一个唯一的第一帧没有按时加载
The first only first frame did not load on on on time
并且动画混合计算不正确
And animation blending was incorrectly calculated
一个非常明显的例子
A very visible example
微小的问题可能会被破坏，而整个片段可能会被破坏
Where the tiny problem can break and entiresegments
这真的不重要
And it's really not important
其余部分有多流畅
How fluent rest of the stuff is
动画怎么样，嗯
How the animation , um
呃，演员们都很流利
Uh , on actors are fluent
资产如何好
How the assets are good
一切都坏掉了
Everything is , uh , broken
第二个方面。对于我们所有的游戏来说，玩家也是非常重要的一个方面
Second aspect . and it's also very important aspect for all our game is the player
这是一个演员
It's an actor
您可以在此示例中看到如何从不同角度呈现一个团队
You can see on this example how one team can be presented from different perspectives
玩家正在积极参与 stm
Player is taking active part of the stm
正因为如此，在大多数情况下
And because of these , in most cases
不可能使用很常见的
It was impossible to use very common
烟镜技术降低生产成本
Smoke and mirror technique to reduce production costs
网络朋克中的玩家可以看到
Player in cyber pank can see
而且这里也比预览中要讨论的内容要多得多。游戏
and also here much more than in previews to depate . the games
第三个方面是女主角还是男主角
Third aspect is female or male protagonist
在赛博朋克中
In cyber punk
百分之九十的场景有两种差异
Ninety percent of the scenes came in two variance
1个4女v，1个男v
One four female v and one for a male v
这增加了对话的复杂性
This increased complexity of the dialogue
在很多情况下，每条 v 线都有两个版本
Each v lines comes in two versions in many cases
响应也有两个版本
Also there are two versions of response
嗯，对于女性 v 来说，samscenes 必须以不同的方式构建
Um samscenes must be constructed differently for the female v
对于主 v 来说则不同
And differently for the main v
最好的例子当然是任何浪漫的事物
The best examples are of course any romance things
但这不仅是因为我们有更多这样的例子
But it's not only that we had much more of those examples
好的
Okay
所以我们已经知道了关键方面
So we already know the key aspects
现在我想进入工具集
Now i want to go to the tool set
我将描述我们的工具以及稍后的方法，呃
And i will describe our tool and later how , uh
展示如何使用它来构建场景结构
Show how to use it to build scene structure
嗯，我们管道的核心是 syeditor
Um , the heart of our pipeline is syeditor
它由四个尖塔预览视图、端口时间线、剧本和，呃，图表组成
It consists four minareias preview view , port timelines , screenplay and , uh , graph
第一个最引人注目的是，呃，预览视口
First most noticeable is , uh , preview viewport
嗯，这就是设计师在之前的会议中组成并修改世界的地方
um , that's where the designer consisting during the previous sessions and modify the world
第二个是时间轴面板，其中包含动画、视觉效果、效果、外观剪辑等事件
Second is the timeline panel with the events like animations , vfx , fx , look cuts
对话活动等
dialogue events and more
接下来，呃，是一张图表
Next , uh , is a graph
我们已经看到了游戏逻辑
We've seen and game logic
最后一个有趣的是屏幕播放
And the last one for interesting is the screen play
带有对话台词和对话选项
With the dialogue lines and dialogue options
一
Um
我想向您展示该图的一些特征
I want to show you a few characteristic of the graph
嗯，是方向
Um , it's direction
现在
Now
在实践中这意味着什么
what it means that in practice
这意味着信号需要来自一个音符的输出
It means that signal needs to go from the output of one note
并转到另一个音符的输入插座
And go to the input socket to the another note
一般而言，节点左侧可以有多个输入和输出
Nodes can have many inputs and outputs on left by general
在左侧我们有输入
On left side we have inputs
在右侧，我们有输出和另一个重要的财产
On the right side we have outputs and another important uproperty
这些套接字没有类型
Those sockets do not have types
因此您可以以任何方式配置笔记并将它们连接到 中
So you can configure the notes and connect them in , in any way
我们有循环的可能性
We have possibility of cycles
这对于页游游戏来说非常重要
And this is quite important in the games , a page game
所以你有很多选择来重复使用对话台词
So you have many options to reuse dialogue lines
而且还可以重用整个任务路径
But also to reuse whole quest paths
嗯，我们有两种类型的节点
Um , we have two types of nodes
这是潜在的笔记和即时的笔记
It's latent notes and immediate notes
只要立即执行操作，后面的注释就会保留信号
Latternotes hold the signal as long as operation is executed immediate
我们的火燃烧而忘记
Our fire fire and forgot
拉丁音符的附加属性是我们能够保存
Additional properties for the latin notes is that we are able to save
呃，到，到，保存他们的进度
Uh , to , to , to save progress of them
并且可以咨询
And can be consult
我们有大量用于不同目的的各种节点
We have plenty of various nodes for different purposes
嗯，但是然后的数量，呃
Um , but amount of then , uh
我们有四个场景的独家注释
We have four exclusive notes for the scenes
首先，重要的节点是节
First , important node is a section
哪个是时间线持有者
And which is timeline holder
第二个是一个选择
Second one is a choice
用于对话分支
Which is used to dialogue branching
我们还有两个额外的具体说明
We have two additional specific notes
但我不会报道它们
But i will be not covering them
嗯，深入了解这个演示
Um , deep in this presentation
这个节点控制 stin 的行为方式
And this node control how the stin should behave
如果出现不可接受的蒸汽进展条件
In case of unaccepted conditions for steam progression
例如，玩家正在退出达里亚或蒸汽
Like for example player is exiting the daria or the steam is
或者例如枪战开始
Or for example the gun fight start
第二个是可重新执行部分，它是该部分的扩展版本
And second one is reendable section it's extended version of the section
具有向后播放的能力
With the ability to play backwards
嗯，还有一些额外的选项可以直接从播放器控制
Um , also have some additional options to control directly from the player
我们在赛博朋克品牌中使用它
We are using it in cyber punk brand ances
部分是专门说明嗯
Section is a note specifically dedicate that um
在图表上创建时间同步序列
To create time synchronized sequences on the graph
在这里你可以看到其中三个
Here you can see three of them
正如您所看到的，它们以非常不同的配置连接
They are , as you see connected in very different configuration
该部分还有哪些内容
What else about the section
章节注释有自己的时间表
Section note have their own timeline
这让设计在低层次上控制正在发生的事情
Which give um design at low level control over what's happening
该团队嗯时间线包含时间地点事件
This team um timeline contains time place events
其中一些有持续时间，例如动画或对话台词
Some of which have duration like animation or dialogue lines
其他只是点事件，例如视觉特效是 lucuts
Other are just point events like vfx is lucuts
时间轴将这些事件存储在轨道上
Timeline stores those events on tracks
你可以在左边看到它突出显示了我们的足迹
And here you see on the left it's highlighted our tracks
为了表明进展，我们有两件事
And to indicate the progress we have two things
一个是播放头
One is playhead
它被标记在轨道旁边
it's marked next to the tracks
并在右上角的计时器处
and on the right top corner at timer
您还可以在其中看到这方面的进展
Where you also can see the the progression of this s
在最右边你可以看到屏幕播放
On the far right you can see screen play
Po屏剧是对话视角的剖面图
Po screen play is a section view for dialogue perspective
用户界面
Ui
您也可以考虑作为作者的数据的欧盟视图
Also you can consider in as eu view of the data for the writer
所以我们支持很多这样的事情，这取决于工作
So we supporting many such things that depending on the job
数据时间的视图不同
The view of data time is be different
现在我们知道了，嗯
Now we know , um
syneitor是如何构建的
How syneitor is constructed
我认为是时候看看它能做什么了
I think that it's time to see what it can do
我们将完成创建蒸汽基本结构的过程
We will go through the process of creating basic structure of the steam
而且，呃，我想重建数码公园现有场景的一部分
And , uh , i want to reconstruct part of existing scene from cyber park
但别担心，呃
But don't worry , uh
这不会是运动大剧透
It will be not sport big spoiler
因为我，我从一开始就选择一个
Because i , i choose one from the beginning
那么我们来看看，呃，游戏中这个场景的一部分
So let's watch , uh , a part of this scene from the game
那么我们就从创建sandbunks环境开始吧，嗯
So let's start from creating sandbunks environment to start , um
这与在红色引擎中创建游戏会话相同
This same to create game session in a red engine
我们需要游戏定义
We need to game definition
这是这个资源，呃
And this is this resource with , uh
小游戏路径设置一下
Small game path to set up it
它有两个参数
It has two parameters
一是参照世界
One is reference to the world
我认为他们不必解释这是什么
I think that they don't have to explain what is it
其次是任务资源
And second is the quest resource
嗯，任务
Um , quest
呃，任务资源包含，嗯
Uh , quest resource contains , um
以开始然后然后并注释的方式绘制图表
Graph with the start and then and note
嗯，在上面的例子中
Um , in a example above
你可以看到，呃，他们之间有一条薄纸条
You can see , uh , thin note between them
还没确定如何开始呃唱姿
It's still not define how to start , uh , singing stance
这是 sting 资源的运行时表示
Which is a runtime representation of sting resource
乌姆斯坦资产
Um stin assets
呃
uh
这就是你所看到的
This is what you see
这是我们的 Acid 浏览器
Here is our acid browser
呃，看起来constance u的每件事都包含这些文件
Uh , looks like every thing constance ucontains those files
首先，嗯，是在解决方案中
First , um , is in solution
呃，是用于编辑目的的 scoptimized 的表格版本
Uh , is ina a table version of scoptimized for editing purposes
而且，嗯，游戏没有加载它
And , um , it's not loaded by the game
这只是为了，为了一个细节
It's only for , for a detail
其次是场景是由加载的资源
Second is a scene is a resource loaded by the
呃，游戏过程中的引擎
Uh , engine during the game session
它针对尺寸和速度进行了优化
And it's optimized for the size and the speed
在编译此 stin 解决方案文件的过程中会创建 Thin fes
the thin fes are creating in the process of compilation of this stin solution file
流程编译由设计者手动启动
Compilation for process is started manually by the designer
嗯，订购费是，呃，支持
Um , order fes are , uh , support
Fes 预制件不是本次测试的专属文件
Fes prefab is not exclusive file for this stin
它是关卡中某些幻灯片的容器
It is container for certain slides of the level
它将包含最重要的元素，例如标记
It will contain most important elements for the things such as a marker
呃
Uh
代表着世界的起源
Which represents in origin in the world
我们将其放在同一个文件旁边以便于文件管理
We keep it next to the same file for easier file management
cn 日志 . json 文件是出于本地化目的导出文本源
Cn log . json file is export of text sources for purpose of localization
而且这个文件也在创建环，呃，编译过程
And this file is also creating to ring , uh , compilation process
在剧本中你可以看到对话台词
In screenplay you can see dialogue lines
在这里你还可以看到我已经创建了，呃，一个部分
And here also you see that i already created , uh , a section
所以一切都是相连的
So everything is connected
，该部分在屏幕上有拨号线 日期和部分有时间线
The , the section have dial lines in the screen day and section have a timeline
里面充满了
Which is filled with
呃，对应于对话台词的对话事件
Uh , dialogue events that corresponds to dialogue lines from
从画面播放
From the screen play
屏幕上值得一提的部分是第九部分
Worth mentioned parts of the screen place are section nine
而且非常有用
And it's very useful
因为我给你看的这个场景很简单
Because this scene which i showed you it's simple
所以它只有一节
So it has only one section
但它可以有很多
But it can be many
所以最好有它以便更快地搜索扬声器
So it's it's better to have it for faster search speaker
这是 Jacky Addressy
Which here is jacky addressy
这是玩家和对话台词
Which here is player and dialogue lines
这部分充满了嗯对话
The section thas is filled with um dialogues
与屏幕播放中的对话台词相对应的事件
Events that correspond to dialogue lines from the screen play
修改屏幕日期自动更新时间轴视图
Modification of screen day automatically update the timeline view
对话幻灯片长度逐步更新
The length of dialogue slides are progressively updated
Fierce 和 pulin 长度
Fierce and pulinary lengths
它是根据文本本身计算的
It's calculated based on text itself
然后从自动生成的画外音中获取长度
Then the length is taken from automatically generated voiceovers
最后是由专业演员录制的记录
And finally from the records recorded but by professional actors
第二个注意点，对于 disets 来说很重要的是选择节点
Second note , which is important for disets are choice nodes
选择笔记有对话选项
Choice notes have dialogue options
就像各个地区都有不同的气候一样
Just like sections have a dioc climes
对话选项，嗯，也在屏幕播放中创建
Dialogue options , um , are also creating in the screen play
国王创建对话选项后
After king creating dialogue option
并且新的套接字出现在选择上
And new socket appears on the choice
在这里你可以看到
Here you can see
我知道这不是很清楚
I know that it's not not very clear
但有两个插座
But there is two sockets
因为我们在这里有两个选择
because we here we have two choice options
一个连接到一个并注意这个红色的
And one is connected to the one and note to this red one
第二个是这个蓝色并注意
And second one is to this blue and note
太好了，嗯，我们有了我们的蒸汽结构
Great , um , we have structure of our steam
Leplay 在《本能》预览中的 stin
Leplay in stin in instinct preview
你会看到它拥有所有元素
And you will see that it has all elements
它有部分选择
It has section choice
它只有演员、台词和对话选项
It has actors , dialogue lines and dialogue options only
缺少的是小牛肉和嘴唇
What is missing is veal and the lips sinu
分期稍后会添加饮料
Staging will add later to drink
演示文稿视图可以使用 google wife 生成
Presentation view can be generated using google wife
可以在生成的画外音之上生成 Net 和 liping
Net and liping can be generated on top of those generated voiceovers
这两个进程都是离线的
Both of those processes are offline
在我们的，嗯，基础设施服务的帮助下实现这一点
Implement that with help of our , um , infrastructure services
所以在这个视频中，嗯
So on this video , um
你会看到我正在开始预览
And you'll see that i'm starting the preview
感人的戏剧和后果
The play that is moving and consequence
一
Um
对话活动围绕
Dialogue events are around
你会看到对话线出现在部分之后
And you see the dialogue lines appearing after section
信号将到达选择节点
And the signal is going to the choice node
五秒后自动
And after five seconds automatically
而选择就是说话
And the choice is speak
信号向右并注意
And the signal goes to the right and note
而且，呃，现在我们已经掌握了所有基础知识
And , uh , now we have all basics
这样我就可以去，呃
So i can go to , uh
实施的第一个描述和
First description of implementation and
这将是信号分配机制
And it will be signal distribution mechanism
我将在这些演示图中使用，呃
I'll be using , uh , in these presentation diagrams
呃，有，而不是，呃，纯代码
Uh , of there instead of , uh , pure code
一
Um
所以这里的条件
So here the condition
大部分煤炭都在这个由点组成的角中
large part and large part of coals are in this raq angles made from dots
用作由破折号组成的三个缠结
Function as three tangles made from the dashes
信号分配从看到状态开始
Signal distribution is started from seeing state
在见过的实例中调用 run
Called run in seen instances
一般来说有很多状态并且不断变化
In general of have many states and changing
但这里将重点关注状态内存
But here will be focused on on state ram
所以，呃，像其他国家一样管理国家
So , uh , state run like others
呃，状态得到，嗯
Uh , states gets , um
呃，来自引擎的浮点增量时间
Uh , floating point delta time from the engine
增量时间用于增加我们的内部场景时钟
Delta time is used to increment our internal scenclock
我们的内部蒸汽钟信誉不佳
Our internal steam clock is discredit
用于简单比较和计算的固定点值（以毫秒为单位）
Fixed point value in milliseconds for trivial comparation and calculations
然后 Sin 时钟转换为时间窗口并传递给处理 token 函数
Sin clock then is convert to the time window and pass to process token function
嗯，执行信号分配的地方
Um , where the signal distribution is perform
关于老年人的一些有趣的事实
Some interesting facts about the senistances
在网络朋克中
And in cyber pank
我们可以同时拥有多达 200 个活动皮肤实例
We can have up to two hundred active skin instances at once
游戏中的 auston 实例最多可以消耗一毫秒
Which can consume maximum one milliseconds for auston instances on the game
适用于任何平台的线程
Thread for any platform
它包括，呃，所有的js
It includes , uh , all the js
并且我们已经对待与外部系统的安全通信
And we have treat safe communication with external systems
给我们一些灵活性也是如此
So is giving us some flexibility
当我们想要时，运行我们的更新
When we want to , to run our updates
基于代币概念的信号分配
Signal distribution in based on token concept
嗯，我们使用令牌的主要假设是能够更新整个图
Um , the main assumption we use tokens was to be able to update an entireon graph
但也有选择性地，嗯
But selectively also to , um
能够传播时间预算
Be able to propagate time budget
预算与信号一起
Budgets together with the signal
拥有那个位置也非常重要
And also very important to have that locality
在这里我们可以看到，嗯
Here we can see the , um
简化的主循环，呃
The simplifying main loop , uh
使用代币安装草的信号有哪些进展
Which progress the signal instsing grass with using tokens
所以在运行之前
So before it's run
立场场景如何开始，因为它已创建
How the scene in stance can start because it's created
然后我们在纸条上放置信号令牌
And then what we are putting signal token on the note
大多数情况下是开始，呃
In most cases is start , uh
现场注意事项
Note of the scene
在节点上放置信号意味着什么
And what means put signal on the node
这意味着我们正在创建信号令牌对象
It means that we are creating signal token object
分配给它的节点id
Assigned to it node id
并将其添加到 ri 中，呃
And add it to the ri , uh
过程中第一个操作就是我们是,嗯
First operation during the the process is that we are , um
将非活动令牌更改为活动令牌
Changing inactive tokento active
如果我们可以将这些不活动标记的目的放在帧之间
If we can purpose of those inactive tokens is to leave between frames
并且能够控制时间预算
And to be able to control time budgets
呃
Uh
所以一个好的例子是
So the good example would be that for example
你不想在这个特定的框架中执行一些节点
You don't want in this particular frame , execute some node
但你想进入，呃，另一个框架
But you want to in , uh , another frame
那么你就将不活动而不是活动
So then you are putting inactive instead of active
状态令牌 信号令牌
State token signal token
对不起
Sorry
信号令牌注释的一部分，嗯
A part of signal token notes , um
注意可以生成e
Note can generate e
执行令牌，呃
Execution token , uh
这允许注释在外部系统上执行
Which gave permission for the note for execution on the external systems
并且不处理也可以生成状态令牌来感知笔记
And also not processing can generate state token to perceive notes
帧之间或游戏会话之间的状态
State between frames or between game sessions
所以token是在节点进程中生成的
So tokens are generated during node process
嗯，我们正在循环，呃
Um , we are looping , uh
执行信号分配循环，直到我们有活跃令牌为止
The loop of signal distribution is executed until we have active tokens
所以直到我们的 ri 中有活跃代币
So until we have in our ri active tokens
我们正在循环，循环
We are looping , looping
循环播放。当它是空的时候
Looping . when it's empty
我们可以拿另一件事为例并做同样的事情
We can take another thing instance and do the same
或者说，它是我们所有系统和处理的结束
Or the , its end of all of our system and processing
关于代币的有趣事实是我们使用，嗯
Interesting facts about the tokens is that we use , um
令牌的一种尺寸
One size for the tokens
所以我们可以将它们存储在ri中
So we can store them in the ri
我非常擅长
And i are very good for
嗯，因为内存局部性和图状态独立于
Um , for memory locality and graph state is independent from the
呃，图表数据
Uh , graph data
所以我们可以进行不同的优化
So we can optimize differently
状态记忆
The memory for the state
对于数据则不同
And differently for , for the data
所以考虑到所有这些
So taking all of that
我们可以减少运行时的内存池
We could reduce the memory pool for the runtime
Sing data , um , to , 兆字节
Sing data , um , to , for mega bytes
对于这么大的游戏来说这已经相当不错了
Which is quite good for such a big game
我们已经有了，呃，基本结构，通常由任务设计师在制作中完成
We already have , uh , basic structure which would be done by the quest designer normally in the production
现在我们去舞台吧，呃
Now let's go to the staging , uh
这是由电影设计师完成的
Which is done by the cinematic designer
我想要的前几个术语，你知道什么是分期
First few terms which i want to , you know what is staging
这就是演员我们的舞台或放置在这个 stm 上来引导玩家的方式
This is how actor our stage or placed at this stm to guide player
并获得最佳可能的图像质量
And get the best possibility image quality
是啊，为了，为了拥有完美的构图
Yeah , to , to have perfect composition
乙
E
您可以将其视为关键职位的作品可以理解为动画
Work you can considering as a key post can be understand as animation
其中不包含很多运动
Which do not contains a lot of motion
呃，在舞台定义的某个位置上
Uh , at its place in some position defined by the staging
呃，工作运动
Uh , worksports
这是工作资源的简称
This is short name for the work resource
呃，为了工作资源
Uh , for the work resource
作品之间的动画
Animation between works
我将称之为过渡和作品，过渡将是
I will be calling transitions and works and transition will be
呃，把一些事件放在时间线上
Uh , placing on timeline as some events
那么让我们开始构建吧
So let's go and let's start building the
分期并完成分期过程
The staging and go through the staging process
首先在我们需要打开的部分
First in the section we need to turn on
将时间线轨道专用于夹克
Dedicate the timeline track for a jacke
你还会看到不仅有一个轨道还有很多子轨道
you will see also that there are not only one track but many subtracks
这是布局的默认行，可以扩展
And this is default line of layout which can be extended
专用轨道，嗯用于组织活动和设置参考
dedicated track , um is for organizing events and out to set references
我们有，嗯，专用轨道
We have , um , dedicated track
现在我将添加更改工作事件
And now i will add change work event
而这次活动专门设置了一个作品
And this event is dedicated to set a work
设置的参数是目标
Parameters to set are the target
所以在我们的例子中它将是 jackie mtt
So in our case it will be jackie mtt
第二个参数是，呃，工作
And second parameter is , uh , work
我会记录一下作品是动画
I will record that work is an animation
或在团队中具有一定位置的简单帖子来选择单词
or simple post with certain placement in a team to select word
我正在使用单词选择器
I'm using word picker
我会把座位安排到需要工作的地方
And i will set seat to hands on nees work
这这这就是这部作品的名字
This , this will be the , the name of this work
正如你所看到的，我们可以有很好的背景
And as you see what we can have nice context
搜索哪个过滤掉，呃，工作体育图书馆
Search which filter out , uh , worksports library
我们对目标实体进行了使用寿命预览
And we have useful life preview with target entity
关于workspuh work picer 本身
About workspuh work picer itself
它正在使用工作簿库
It's using workbook librari
哪一组工作导出按命名约定按类别排序
Which is set of work exports sorted in categories with naming convention
允许快速搜索锻炼库
Which allowing quick search workout library
您可以将其想象为包含工作资源的文件夹的地图视图
You can imagine as map view of folders with work resources
呃，我在这里展示了两个通用配置的作品
Uh , i'm showing here two works in common configuration
呃，除了闲置动画之外还添加了其他内容
Uh , where additional were addition to the idle animation
具有附加动画以随机方式播放
Has additive animation to played in sell the random manner
其目的是增加本能中看到的动画的多样性
The purpose of it is to increase variety of animations seen in instincts
而且它也让游戏变得更加有趣，对于玩家来说
And also it makes it led more interesting for , for the player
好的
Okay
所以我们，呃，安排工作
So we have , uh , set work
嗯，我要开始预览了
Um , i will start the preview
可以看到jackie立马把默认的作品改了
You can see that the jackie immediately changed the work from the default
从活动开始工作
Work to work from the event
呃，这个大招有效
Uh , and this ult work
我们去偶像摊
We are going idol stand
呃，尽管事实上这是一个循环执行动画的点事件夹克
Uh , despite the fact that it's a point event jacket performed animation in loop
作品不是单一的动画
Work is not a single animation
它是实体的整个逻辑ai状态
It is whole logical ai state of entity
现在是转场，呃，让我们看看进一步添加作品和转场的过程
Now transitions , uh , so let's look at the further process of adding works and transitions
我添加另一个变更工作事件
I add another change work event
这次我卖的是一只鹿自动转出
And this time i'm selling transition a deer automatically deout
之前是什么姿势
What pose was before
一
Um
并在选择后建议匹配的转换，嗯
And suggest the transition that matches , um , after selecting
还注意到工作也出来了选择这个能力来扣除
also noted that work is also also out to selected this ability to deduct
演员在某个时刻之前的状态是什么
What the state of the actor is before certain moment
结合适当的命名约定
Combined with proper naming convention
这对设计师来说是一个很大的速度笑话
It's a big speed gag for designer
等等 。最重要的是
And so on . top of that
如果您可以从看到图表的任何时刻开始预览
If you can start preview from any moment of seeing graph
然后你将拥有非常好的快速实现和迭代循环
Then you will have really nice fast implementation and iteration loop
我们无力记录
We cannot afford to record
作品之间所有过渡组合的所有动画
All animations for all combination of transitions between works
这只是物理上不可能的
It's just physically not possible
我们没有，我们没有这方面的预算
And we don't have we didn't have budgets for for that
所以下一个三节课
So next tris session
我需要选择手动盟友
I need to select manual ally
我在工作中关掉过滤器
I turn off the filter in work
呃，选择器和，呃，设置为最适合我的场景的过渡
Uh , picker and , uh , set for the best fitting transition to my scene
预记录转换和一般记录之间的平衡处于我们正在飙升的位置
These balance between pre records transitions and general ones is placed where we are surging
削减生产成本
Cut of production costs
好的，我们已经有了所有的姿势
Okay , so we have all poses
让我们看看皮肤是什么样子的
Let's see how the skin looks like
与上一届会议的结构工作和过渡
With the structure works and transitions in previous session
再次
Again
我们开始预览
We starting the preview
你会看到类似的
You will see that similar
我喜欢上一个视频
I like on the previous video
呃，我们正在移动播放头，对话台词出现了
Uh , we are moving the the playhead and the dialogue lines appeared
但也运行相应的转换
But also the corresponding transitions are run
杰基也在改变中间的姿势
And jackie is changing also the the poses in between
因此，放置在该场景中或该场景的一部分的可能性非常重要
So this is very important that this possibility to place in or part of this scene
刚换完后
Just after changing
对场景进行更改极大地缩短了实施时间
Make the changes to the scene is extreme boost in implementation time
现在我们准备进行第二次实现
So now we are ready to go to the second implementation
我想展示的是事件处理和执行
Which i want to show is events processing and execution
我们已经知道发生了什么
We already know what are the events
以及它们在编辑器中的位置
And where they are in editor
在内部，时间线轨道不存在
Internally , timeline track do not exist
但我把它们放在这里是为了更方便
But i keep them here for easier
了解活动的概念和实施
Understanding of the concept and implementation of the events
包含 id 、开始时间
Contains id , start time
水龙头类型和 partype 专用参数
Tap type and partype dedicated parameters
呃，在过程部分中，像任何其他部分一样获得时间预算
During uh , section process section gets time budget like any and out
而这个预算就转化为时间窗口
And this budget is transformed into time window
哪一个和这里左边的两个重要属性是包容性的
Which and here two important properties on left is inclusive
右侧不包含在内
On the right side is not inclusive
时间窗口之外的内容是执行的
What is outside of the time window was execute that
或将在未来被处决
Or will be executed in the future
但是我们对包容性和包容性网站的理解是，嗯
But what we understand by inclusive and ninclusive sites of the , um
时间窗口在这里
Time window here
你可以在幻灯片上看到，呃，这一事件
You can see , uh , on the slide that one event
开始时间到了。它等于时间窗口的开始时间
It start time . it's equal to the start time of the time window
在这个框架中我们将执行这个 um 事件
And in this frame we will execute this um event
但我们还有第二个活动
but we have also second an event
本次活动具体开始时间
Which start time of this event
在这些人中，点事件等于时间窗口的结束事件
Point event is equal to end event of time window in such guys
该帧中的该事件不会被执行
This event in this frame will be not executed
并且会在下一帧执行
And it will be executed in the next frame
偶数处理从确定偶数的位置开始
The even processing begins with determining the position of the
呃，呃，当然事件过程，呃
Uh , uh , course event course of , uh
基于时间窗口
Based on time window
然后我们迭代事件直到到达事件
And then we iterate through events until we get to the event
哪个不包含在时间窗口内
Which is not contained by the time window
这不是重叠
It's not overlap
一
Um
我们创建动作部分
We creating action parts
在处理当前有关动作部分的事件期间
During this processing of events about action parts in the moment
现在，让我们集中精力，呃
For now , let's focus that , uh
我们可以根据事件的活动生成不同的动作部分
We can generate different action parts depending on activity of the event
而且，那就是，嗯
And , and that's , um
该活动的活动，呃，是
Activity , uh , of the event is
确定时间窗口如何与事件重叠
Determine how , uh , time window overlap the event
如果时间窗口包含事件的开始，则开始活动
And if the time window contains the beginning of the event , it start activity
如果窗口与事件的中间部分重叠
If the window overlap the middle part of the event
然后是常规活动
Then its regular activity
如果末端被覆盖，它的和活动
And if the end is covered , its and activity
evin的各个动作部分按动作键排列
the evin individual action parts are arranged by action key
排序后，动作部分将按类型分组
in such a way that after sorting the action parts will be grouped by the type
并且将执行具有最高属性的动作部分
And action part with the highest perty will be performed
第一个组合器是用于对类型中的操作部分进行排序的附加参数
First combiner is additional parameter to sort action part within a type
因此，组合错误可以例如将执行的目标 id
so combine error can for example target id on which will perform
所以我们可以，例如，首先为第一个mtt做动作部分
So we can , for example , first do action part for first mtt
然后是第二个和第三个
Then for the second and the thir
我认为现在是扩展的好时机
i think that is a good moment to expand
为什么我们要创建这些动作和动作部分
Why we are creating those actions and action parts
并且不直接对事件执行
And not executing directly on the from the events
应考虑速度来优化执行过程
Execution process should be optimized with taking into into account speed
依赖性
Dependency
解析和外部系统特性
Resolving and external system characteristics
为了满足这些要求
To meet those requirements
我们使用，嗯，动作
We use , um , actions
这给了我们独立的分离和灵活性
Which give us separate separation and flexibility
与事件相反，动作和动作部分是在 rin time 中创建的
Action and action parts , in contrast to events are created in rin time
具有良好的分拣能力
Have good sorting capabilities
因为他们是在运行时创建的
And because they are creating in runtime
我们关于 stm 实例内的依赖关系吗
Are our about dependences within stm instances
好的
Okay
所以我们通过处理部分
So we pass the the part with the processing
现在执行并执行操作
Now execution and the execution of the operation
首先根据操作键对操作路径进行排序
Begin with the sorting of action paths based on action keys
我们在上一张幻灯片中讨论的内容
Those which we are talking about on the previous slide
然后将动作部分添加到动作中
Then the action parts are added to the action
动作和动作部分之间的关​​系是动作包含执行代码
A rela relationship between action and action part is that action contains execution code
使用动作部分作为参数
Which use action parts as a parameters
最后，呃，动作被执行了
Finally , the actions , uh , are performed
执行时可能会导致
Which may result as execution
嗯，外部系统或作曲家
Um , external system or composer
作曲家是，嗯，模特
Composer is , um , model
负责同一目标上不同tm实例之间的分发操作
Responsible for distributing operation between different tm instances on the same target
例如，一个
For example , um
如果你想
If you want
如果同时运行几个场景
If you have few scenes running at the same time
他们正在访问玩家
And they are accessing player
所以我们需要一些层来检测冲突或
So we need some layer which will be detecting the conflicts or
或者决定应该先做什么
Or deciding what should be first
其次应该是什么
And what should be second
最后，我想向您展示预览会话是如何进行的
At the end , i want to show you how the preview session
呃，按比例工作
Uh , works in the scale
一
Um
我将运行
And i will run the
前一届最终版场景加载了夜城视频
The previous session of the final version of the scene with night city loaded videos
口型同步和后期处理
Lip sync and post processes
嗯，我知道也许你不在这里溜冰场
Um , i know that maybe you are not here rink
声音，嗯
The voice , um
但抱歉，我现在不会修复
But sorry that i , i will not fix right now
但您会看到比预览更多的内容
But you will see much more than on the preview
预览，预览会议肯定
Preview , preview session for sure
所以它看起来与你在游戏中看到的非常相似
so it looks pretty identical to what you see in game
是的，所以你可以改变相机的姿势
Yeah , so you can pose change the camera
是的
Yeah
玩家没有经历过这很有趣
player do not have had it's pretty funny
是的，我们可以回到fpp来吧
yeah ， we can go back to fpp come around
好的
Okay
我们来总结一下
Let's go to summary
所以在我的演讲之后
So after my presentation
你知道第一人称视角是，呃
And you know that first person perspective was , uh
当我们设计和实现工具集中的许多东西时，这是一个重要的部分
Important part when we are designing and implementation and implementing many things in the toolset
而且你知道，男女主角不仅仅是游戏设置统计中的参数
And you know that female and male protagonist is not just parameter in the game setting statistics
这是创建呃场景系统时的重要特征
It's important characteristic when creating , uh , scene system
我给你看了 sca itor
I showed you sca itor
我在实践中使用场景结构和场景分期
And i did for use scene structure with the scenes staging in practice
我们完成了信号分配
We went through the signal distribution
其中使用了代币并了解其工作原理以及是什么
Which used tokens and learn how it works and what is
这是相当简单的实现
And that is quite light implementation
在最后
At the end
我们使用动作来分解执行过程
We decompose even execution process with use of actions
谢谢你和我在一起
Thank you for being with me
我希望您在我的演讲中发现一些有趣的内容
i hope that you found something interesting for you in my presentation
您未来的游戏可以从中受益
And your future games can benefit from it
并且有这个机会
And having this opportunity
我不会说我们正在招聘
I won't say that we are hiring
所以如果您有兴趣与我们合作
So if you are interested in working with us
例如，在这样的交互式合成技术上
For example , on such interactive syntech
请联系我们
Please reach out us
保持健康，保持安全
Stay healthy , stay safe
谢谢
Thank you
呃，谢谢你
Uh , thank you
谢谢你，菲利普
Thank you , philip
呃
Uh
那真是一次了不起的，呃，会议
That was an amazing , uh , session
呃，呃，正在看这些视频
Uh , was , uh , looking at these videos
这个例子我们使用
And this example we use
右手真是鼓舞人心。因为，呃
The right hand was really inspiring . because , uh
我一直在看屏幕的右侧
I was looking on the right side of the screen
光滑的手经过的地方
Where the smooth hand passing by
屏幕左侧还有这个噗哈哈快手
And the left side the screen with this po ha ha quick hand
哇，你做的真是太棒了
And wow , that's an amazing job you doing
我可以看到那些小细节，呃，那个
I can see those small details , uh , that
呃
Uh
提高游戏的最终质量
Increase the final quality of the game
是的
Yeah
它是
It's
我的意思是，经常
I mean , it's often
你知道，我睡不着
You know , i couldn't sleep
因为，呃，那些包
Because , uh , of the , those bags
而且他们压力真的很大
And they are really stressful
我的意思是，是的，我想你可以比较一下
I mean , it is , i think that you can compare it
可能有
And probably there is
呃，一些，一些从事VR工作的人
Uh , some , some people who was working on vr
还有这个fpp也很重要
And there is also very important this fpp
并且不要，你知道，做
And do not , you know , doing
相机带来如此不同的东西
Such different things with the camera
因为你可以获得运动的乐趣
Because you can get motion snice
当我修复这些问题时
And i literally when i was fixing those
那些袋子和抛光这些东西
Those bags and polishing this stuff
我真的，呃，压力很大
I really , uh , it , it was very stressful
是的
Yeah
而且，你知道，你不能拒绝
And , and you couldn't , you know , say no
它是 。已经足够好了
It's . it's good enough
不，它需要平滑
No , it's need to be smooth it
如果不顺利的话
If it will be not smooth
整个顺序被打破了
The whole sequence is , is broken
和 , 和
And , and
是的
And yeah
是、非常重要
It's , it's very important
是的
Yeah
我可以，我，我可以联系
I can , i , i can relate
你知道
You know
当有一个小 , 嗯
When there's a small , um
不顺畅，你知道，它就在那里
Unsmoothness that , you know , that there it is
而且，你知道你可以处理它，但你不能只是，呃
And , you know that you can deal with it and you can't just , uh
忘记它吧
Just forget about it
是的
Yeah
我，我完全明白
I , i totally understand that
感谢你所做的一切
And thank you for what you are doing
因为，呃，我相信这一点，而完美就是，呃
Because , uh , i believe that and perfection is , uh
就像您为我们的产品增添了巨大的价值一样
Like you add significant value to our products
谢谢
Thank you
非常感谢
Thank you very much
呃，谢谢你今天加入我们
Uh , so thank you for joining us today
呃
Uh
感谢您精彩的演讲
Thank you for your amazing presentation
呃
Uh
所以各位，请阅读这个松木版的演示文稿，嗯
So guys , please read this presentation in pine , um
如果您在 YouTube 上观看此内容，请按 YouTube 上的“赞”按钮
Press the like buttons on youtube if you are watching this on youtube
感谢您今天加入我们
And thanks for joining us today
感谢翻转，希望下次再见
Thank flip and hope to see you next time
非常感谢
Thank you very much
西姆再见
Sium bye